Nathaniel Flores

Front End Web and Software Developer | nathanielflores.com | 832-707-9833 | floresnathaniel83@gmail.com

Objective

I'm looking for a position on a team as a front-end developer to improve business processes and marketing for e-commerce organizations by developing better web experiences, EAS (enterprise application software) and SaaS (Software as a service)

About

For the past 10 years I have built a career in retail management and customer service. I have always had a passion and curiosity for information technology and computers and how it relates to business models and processes. At the beginning of this year I decided to make a change. I really wanted to challenge myself and get out of my comfort zone. I started to research different areas in IT and fell into many hours of coding tutorials. It was then that I realized how much I love the craft of programming. I think it's amazing that what I can build can help solve many problems facing businesses and even society today. That is something I want to be a part of

Skills

My biggest achievement to date is Vinyl Pi, a full stack trading application for vinyl aficionados. Users are able to trade records and share their story about how they got into collecting records, inspiring further exploration into under-appreciated genres and record labels. I built it using JavaScript, HTML, CSS and React on the client side and Mongoose, Express, MongoDb on the server side. I utilized a flux architecture created with Underscore, Backbone and iQuery

BASIC TOOLS

I use these basic tools for my everyday workflow

- Basic terminal usage
- GitHub basics
- Basic SSH
- Sublime Text Editor

HTML5/CSS3

I have exposure to user interface and user experience interactions and layouts that are fully responsive by understanding what the user and client needs are through meticulous wire-framing, prototyping and development planning

- Sass
- Scss
- Skeleton
- Bootstrap
- Responsive design with CSS

JAVASCRIPT

I started out building my first projects using pure JavaScript and as my applications became more complex I started to implement different architectures, frameworks and libraries

- Backbone.js
- React.js
- jQuery
- Underscore
- MVC architecture
- Flux architecture
- Browserify
- Bower/package management
- ES6/ES2015 (Babel)

NODE.JS

I have exposure to server side programming. For my app, Vinyl Pi, I wrote my own API and created a database to save user information

- Express
- Mongoose
- MongoDB
- MongoChef
- PostMan
- API's/RESTful services/GET POST PUT DELETE requests

- Heroku web platform
- Understanding of how the client and server talk to each other

Education

May 2001 to August 2005

University of Texas | Arlington, TX

I earned a bachelor's degree in International Business. I graduated cum laude with a 3.5 cumulative GPA

Experience

May 2016 to August 2016

Front-End Engineer | The Iron Yard | Houston, TX

12-week intensive front end engineering bootcamp

Developed fully responsive web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, and Bootstrap

Developed web applications using MVC and Flux frameworks Backbone.js and React.js

Developed web applications with server side logic using API/RESTful services, Express, Mongoose and MongoDB

September 2011 to August 2015

General Manager | Teavana | Houston, TX

As a General Manager, my daily requirement was to exceed sales plan for the month by leading in personal sales, motivating and coaching a team through standard sales processes

June 2007 to September 2011

Assistant Manager | Starbucks Coffee Company | Houston, TX

As an Assistant Manager, my daily requirement was to coach and mentor partners to achieve excellent customer service and coffee standards and analyze sales reports to increase profits and control cost